Chanusha Kaushal Gunarathne

147, Main Street, Buttala

MOBILE : +94 712774638 RESIDENCE : +94 552273332

E-MAIL : chanushakaushal1@gmail.com



PROFILE



Enthusiastic in exploring new learning horizons in Information Technology, which challenges my thinking and demands me to bring about a positive change in organizations. I am interested in acquiring knowledge and experience in the aspect of quality assurance. My career goal is to continuously grow in technical capacity whilst enriching management and leadership skills.

EDUCATION

BSc Special (Hons) – Information Technology Specialization – Information Technology Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology Feb 2017

Passed G.C.E Advanced Level Examination in Biological Science Stream

Aug 2010

Siridhamma College - Galle

WORK EXPERIENCE

Virtusa (Pvt) Ltd.

No: 752, Dr. Danister De Silva Mw, Dematagoda, Colombo 09

Associate Software Quality Assurance Engineer (11 Months) Software Quality Assurance Engineer (1 Year) March 2017 - Jan 2018 Feb 2018 - Present

CORE COMPETENCIES

Software Quality Assurance

Experience with manual testing

Experiences in Defect management process

Knowledge of testing approaches and techniques

Business Management

Photography

Demonstrated skills in leadership

Good analyzing and analytical skills

Good problem solving skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

QA Tools & Technologies	HP ALM Quality Center, Selenium Web Driver, Soap UI
Other Tools & Technologies	Eclipse, NetBeans, GIT, Putty, FileZilla, MS Word, MS Excel
Languages	Java, HTML
DBMS & Tools	MSSQL, MYSQL, PL/SQL, Toad for Oracle

CERTIFICATION

Certificate in Certified Tester Foundation Level (CTFL) International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)	Dec 2018
Certificate in Java Standard Edition Industrial Master (PVT) Ltd	April 2016
Certificate in Web designing WinSys Networks (PVT) Ltd	June 2015
Workshop on Network Cabling, CCTV Installation and PABX Intercom and Wireless Network Training Program WinSys Networks (PVT) Ltd	Dec 2014
Certificate in English Language	Sep 2012

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

British Council, Sri Lanka

Recommendation System for Online Social Network Recruiting – Research

Develop a LinkedIn based Applicant Recommendation system as a decision support system for Organizational recruitment process. System included trust model and progress model for recommend the applicant.

My English Teacher – Project

February 2015 – April 2015

Android application for English learning tool for Nursery children and absolute beginners. Featured with speech recognition, Text to speech, online assignments, Wikipedia search, YouTube search and user profile ranking features.

Gunarathne Stores Management System – Project

June 2014 - November 2014

Develop a java based standalone application for wholesale distribution company Gunarathne Stores to manage their business functions by using computerized approach.

ASP.Net web site for online media store - Project

June 2013 - October 2013

Developed a website having capabilities of user registration and login and place orders with shopping cart.

INDUSTRIAL PROJECTS

Project NYL LTC Agent Commission Phase 2

Associate Engineer- QA Engineer- QA

April 2017 – Jan 2018 Feb 2018 – Dec 2018

Date: 01/21/2019

Description

NYL LTC is in the process of migrating its current Long-term care agent commissions operations from LTCG to BASIS platform. LTCG is transferring the data that is needed for agent commission calculation to a new application called BASIS through feed files. Virtusa QA team is performing the testing on the new commissions platform to ensure that new commission platform cater the LTC business needs.

Responsibilities

- Planning, monitoring, and control of the testing activities and tasks.
- Having an ownership of test data management (test data creation & test data loading)
- Maintain required domain knowledge within the team.
- Requirement Analysis and Test designing.
- Conducting peer reviews on the deliverables (Test Designs, Test Cases etc.)
- Participate in SQA reviews, requirement clarification and walk-through sessions.
- Test Execution (functional, and Regression testing).
- Back-end Test execution Database configurations and testing through Oracle SQL.
- Communicate with onsite team about release progress and production issues.
- Test case, test result and defect tracking in ALM.
- Collaborative working with development teams to get the defects fixed based on severity and priority.

REFEREES

Ms. Nipuni Udarika Ms. Nadeesha Lakmini Senior Consultant - QA Consultant - QA Virtusa Pvt.Ltd, Virtusa Pvt.Ltd,

752, Dr Danister De Silva Mawatha, 752, Dr Danister De Silva Mawatha,

Colombo 09, Sri Lanka. Colombo 09, Sri Lanka. Mobil: 071-6020025 Mobil: 077-1504468

I hereby declare that the above particulars are true and accurate to the best of my knowledge.

Chanusha Kaushal Gunarathne